<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Portrait of Dr. Robert Levy</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Sydney Houtrie</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">between 1930-1939</dateCreated></originInfo><language><languageTerm type="text">Inscription is in English.</languageTerm></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 14 x 11 inches, black and white</extent><note>Handwritten on the back of the photograph: ''Dr. Robert Levy, gift from daughter: Mrs. Sam Rose (Marian).''</note><form>Photographic prints</form></physicalDescription><abstract>Formal portrait of Dr. Robert Levy. Dr. Robert Levy came to Denver in 1879 as a student at the University of Denver.  He started practicing medicine in Denver in 1884 after training at Bellevue Hospital.  He was an organizer, in 1890,  of the Jewish Hospital Association of Denver, which later became National Jewish Hospital. Dr. Levy was a longtime board member of National Jewish and was chairman of the Medical Advisory Board. He was also instrumental in the organization of Denver Clinical Pathological Assn. and, in 1887, of Gross Medical College, which later merged into DU's medical school.  Dr. Levy's specialty was ear, nose and throat, and during World War I he was in charge of that specialty at Fort Lewis.  He practiced medicine in Denver for 60 years, and was honored by a testimonial dinner at National Jewish Hospital in 1944.  He was also on the board of Temple Emanuel, and served as president of the Denver and Colorado medical societies.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note type="admin">Donated by Mirian Levy Rose, daughter of Dr. Robert Levy, December 25, 1976.</note><note type="admin">ph14</note><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Levy, Robert--Dr.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>National Jewish Hospital (U.S.)</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Health Care and Philanthropy</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.03.0031.0003.00001</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:64671</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>