<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Anti-Defamation League Catholic-Jewish Dialogue</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><role><roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1/13/1965</dateCreated></originInfo><language><languageTerm type="text">Inscription is in English.</languageTerm></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 9 x 11 inches, black and white</extent><note>Typed on a piece of paper taped to the back of the photograph: ''Catholic and Jewish leaders gather for recent Conference on ''Attitudes and Images - A Catholic - Jewish Dialogue'' at Regis College sponsored by the College and the Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith.  More than 300 persons attended the one-day session.  Shown above are, l. to r., former Judge Charles Rosenbaum, member of the ADL's National Executive Committee, Oscar Cohen, New York; ADL National Program Director and opening speaker at the conference; James Reed, Denver attorney and Christian Family Movement leader, chairman of the opening session; The Rev. Francis J. Malecek, S.J., Assistant Professor of Philosophy at Regis College, Chairman of the Conference Steering Committee; Mrs. Don Burton, Christian Family Movement, member of the steering committee.''</note><form>Photographic prints</form></physicalDescription><abstract>Left to right former Judge Charles Rosenbaum, member of the ADL's National Executive Committee; Oscar Cohen, ADL National Program Director and opening speaker at the conference; James Reed, Denver attorney and Christian Family Movement leader and chairman of the opening session; the Rev. Francis J. Malecek, S. J., assistant professor of Philosophy at Regis College and chairman of the conference steering committee; and Mrs. Marilyn Burton from the Christian Family Movement and member of the steering committee during an Anti-Defamation League Catholic-Jewish Dialogue meeting at Regis College in Denver.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note type="admin">Donated by Anti-Defamation League.</note><note type="admin">ph555</note><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Rosenbaum, Charles</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Cohen, Oscar</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Reed, James</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Malecek, Francis J.--Rev.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Burton, Marilyn</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>B'nai B'rith.--Anti-defamation League.--Mountain States Regional Office</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>Regis College (Denver, Colo.)</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Organizations</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.04.0037.00003</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:64062</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>