<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Dedication of the First Synagogue of the Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><role><roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1907</dateCreated></originInfo><language></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 7 x 10 inches, black and white</extent><note>Handwritten on envelope: ''#18 First tent synagogue of the JCRS, 1905''.  On back of photograph: ''#17 Dedication of first synagogue of the Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society 1907.   Please credit American Jewish Archives on the Cincinnati Campus of the Hebrew Union College - Jewish Institute of Religion Amer. Jewish Arch. 32361''. Typed note inside original envelope states: ''Jan. 30, 1962. From Mrs. Herman H. Auerbach 601 South Thirty-First Street  Omaha 5, Nebraska    Two photographs of the dedication, in about 1907, of the first synagogue tent on the grounds of struggling Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society sanitarium, then headed by a Dr. C.D. Spivak, originally from Philadelphia.   My mother, Bath-Seva Fleishman - - not a rich person - - donated the funds to build this little tent-synagogue because she felt that sick people needed the solace of a place to worship. Mother never saw the tent, except in this photo. She died in 1918.  In the early 1920's, a Denver citizen gave the funds ($20,000) I think) to replace the tent with a little brick chapel - - I think his name was Rude) and so the officials of the sanitarium dedicated a bed, marked with a plaque, in her honor  One picture shows the tent-synagogue; and the other picture shows the crowd in attendance at the dedication.  Se photos # 17 and 18''</note><form>Photographic prints</form></physicalDescription><abstract>Dedication of the first synagogue of the Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society (JCRS), in 1907. There is a large crowd gathered around the synagogue, which was a tent erected with the help of donor Bath-Seva Fleishman. The JCRS was a sanatorium for tuberculosis patients that was founded in 1904 by a group of immigrant Jewish workingmen along with the support of several leading physicians and rabbis in Denver, Colorado. The sanatorium was located on West Colfax Avenue just outside of Denver.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note type="admin">ph18</note><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society (U.S.)</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Health Care and Philanthropy</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.03.0003.00002</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:64386</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>