<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Cancer Treatment at the AMC Cancer Research Center and Hospital</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><role><roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">between 1950-1970</dateCreated></originInfo><language></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 10 x 8 inches, black and white</extent><note>Handwritten on envelope: ''#463 AMC Cancer Research Center and Hospital''.  On back of photograph: ''Cancer treatment AMC.''</note><form>Photographic prints</form></physicalDescription><abstract>A female patient receiving treatment for cancer at the American Medical Center (AMC) Cancer Research Center and Hospital in Denver Colorado. AMC was located on the grounds of the former Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society (JCRS). The JCRS was a sanatorium for tuberculosis patients that was founded in 1904 by a group of immigrant Jewish workingmen along with the support of several leading physicians and rabbis in Denver, Colorado. The sanatorium was located on West Colfax Avenue just outside of Denver. In the 1950s, the institution reincorporated as the American Medical Center and became one of the first dedicated cancer institutions in the nation.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note type="admin">Accession # 1271, Donated by AMC Cancer Research Center as part of the JCRS Records.</note><note type="admin">ph463</note><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>American Medical Center (Denver, Colo.)</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Health Care and Philanthropy</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.03.0036.00003</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:64779</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>