<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>National Council of Jewish Women, Denver Section, Kosher Picnic at Leadville, Colorado</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><role><roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">7/28/1895</dateCreated></originInfo><language></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 8 x 10  inches, black and white</extent><note>On front of photograph: ''To the Council of Jewish Women, Denver, Colo. Compliments of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred A. Freedheim. Jewish Picnic given at Leadville, Colo. complimenting Miss Sadie American touring the U.S. organizing the Councils of Jewish Women, July 28, 1895.'' ''See Rear'' is inked on front of photograph. Handwritten on the back of the photograph: ''Souvenir of a Gala day at Twin Lakes, July 28-95. Standing Mrs. Saidi Lands, x, Dr. Sol G. Kahn, Mr. Sol Garrett, x, Martha Kafiski, Mrs. Adolph Bair, Miss Sadie American, Mrs. Carrie Mayer, Alfred A. Freedham, Grace Diamond. In Bus: Bus Driver, Mr. Ben Brown, Amelia Friedlander, x, Alfred Huffman, x, Tillie Kahn, Mother of Sadie American, x, Son of Mrs. Adolph Bair, Mr. Rosenbush, x.'' ''x Deceased.'' Typed on paper attached to the back of the photograph: Contact: Janice Rosen 721-6766. Caption for Photo Accompanying Attached Article for Release June 3, 1988. In 1895 the young organization set out to attract attention to their organization and increase membership. Denver Section hosted a visit from Miss Sadie American who was touring the country to help form new sections. Trips into the mining communities of Colorado were arranged. This picture was taken on an excursion to Leadville.''</note><form>Photographic prints</form></physicalDescription><abstract>A group of men and women in  and in front of a horse drawn wagon. Standing in front of the wagon left to right: Mrs. Saidi Lands, Dr. Sol G. Kahn, Sol Garrett,  Martha Kafiski, Mrs. Adolph Bair, Miss Sadie American, Mrs. Carrie Mayer, Alfred A. Freedham, and Grace Diamond. On the wagon: unidentified man,  Ben Brown (driver), Amelia Friedlander (holding sign), Alfred Huffman, Tillie Kahn, the Mother of Sadie American, the Son of Mrs. Adolph Bair, and Mr. Rosenbush. The group participates in a Jewish picnic at Twin Lakes in Leadville, Colorado.  Amelia Freedlander holds a sign that reads, ''This Way Kosher Picnic.''  The word ''Kosher'' is in Hebrew. 
The Denver Section of the National Council of Jewish Women (NCJW) hosted the picnic to honor Sadie American who was touring the country to help form new sections of NCJW.  The Denver Section was founded in 1893, the same year the national organization was established to promote Jewish education, philanthropy, and social reform. The early group of women worked to offer aid and to Americanize East European immigrants at the turn of the 20th Century.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note>Appears in ''Images of America: Jewish Denver 1859-1940,'' by Dr. Jeanne Abrams, page 74.</note><note type="admin">Given to the National Council of Jewish Women by Mr. and Mrs. Arthur A. Friedheim. Arthur A. Friedheim is one of the people in the photograph. National Council of Jewish Women, Denver Section donated it to Beck Archives in December 1976.</note><note type="admin">ph58</note><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>American, Sadie,--1862-1944</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Lands, Saidi</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Kahn, Sol G.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Garrett, Sol</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Kafiski, Martha</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Bair, Adolph--Mrs.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Mayer, Carrie</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Freedham, Alfred A.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Diamond, Grace</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Brown, Ben</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Friedlander, Amelia</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Huffman, Alfred</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Kahn, Tillie</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Rosenbush--Mr.</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>National Council of Jewish Women.--Denver Section</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Organizations</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.04.0031.0009.00001</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:64054</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>