<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Collage of Cook, Battock, and Hayutin Businesses</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource><originInfo><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><place><placeTerm type="text">Denver, Colorado</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">between 1900-1930</dateCreated></originInfo><language></language><physicalDescription><extent>1 item (photograph), 14 x 11 inches, black and white</extent><note>Handwritten on the back of the photograph: ''#57, Collage of Mrs. Harry Cook & Daughter of Cook's Baths. She was known as 'Dis Bakerkeh' in charge of the Mikveh.'; Mr. Harry Battock, peddler on fruit wagon; Motorcycle shop of Morris Hayutin; Donors: Mr. Louis Cook, Mrs. Mary Kreisman, Mr. Peryle H. Beck.''</note><form>Photographic prints</form><digitalOrigin>Reformatted digital</digitalOrigin></physicalDescription><abstract>The upper left photograph shows Ida Cook and her daughter standing in front of a house. Harry and Ida Cook owned the Cook's Russian Baths in Denver, Colorado. At night, the Baths served as a mikveh (ritual bath) that was operated for women by Ida Cook. During the day the Baths served as a popular steam bath open to the public, complete with catered kosher meals. The upper right photograph shows Harry Battock, who came to Denver to be treated at the Jewish Consumptives' Relief Society, and peddled fruit and vegetables from a horse-drawn wagon on Denver's west side. The bottom photograph shows Morris Hayutin behind a motorcycle, underneath a canopy. There is another motorcycle beside Morris Hayutin and several cars are parked behind the canopy. Morris Hayutin's bicycle and motorcycle business, the Western Supply Company, was located on the corner of 15th and Larimer streets in Denver.</abstract><note>Title supplied by archivist.</note><note type="admin">Donated by Peryle Hayutin Beck, daughter of Morris Hayutin.</note><note type="admin">ph57</note><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Cook, Ida</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Hayutin, Morris S.,--1889-1974</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="personal"><namePart>Battock, Harry</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>Western Supply Company</namePart></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"><namePart>Cook's Russian Bath House (Denver, Colo.)</namePart></name></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject></subject><relatedItem><titleInfo><title>Beck Archives Photograph Collection, Businesses</title></titleInfo></relatedItem><identifier type="local">B063.01.0029.0003.00001</identifier><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:59488</url></location><accessCondition type="useAndReproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition></mods>