<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Place Names in the Grand Canyon National Park</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Chapparo, Susan</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1987</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>The study of place-names presents a fascinating insight into the hopes, values, and interests of past generations. And perhaps nowhere is this truer than in the United States, where in most cases it is known who first used a name given to a particular feature on the landscape. When the immigrants first came to the eastern shores of North America, they brought with them many treasured memories of their lives in the old world. And the names they placed on the features of this new land were often taken from places they had known before. Then after the American Revolution, great new territories were opened up in the West, and explorers and settlers in these regions often used names reflecting their hopes and dreams. They also met new peoples who had their own names for many natural features, which were then assimilated, often in corrupted forms, into the American language. An example of a name of this kind is Magotsu Creek in Utah, which was taken from the Pah Ute Indian phrase Mahautsu, meaning &quot;long slope&quot;. Many settlements in these newly occupied areas bloomed briefly and as quickly died out, leaving behind only intriguing names and the stories surrounding them. But the names of many of the natural features survived. After much of the West had been at least sparcely settled, its unique and spectacular landforms were located and extensively explored. Many of these areas had been first seen years before by white men, and of course the Indians knew of them, but they were considered either tall tales, or were placed on maps that so poorly showed their true position that no one could find them again. Thus these natural wonders were likely &quot;discovered&quot; many times before being reliably mapped and systematically explored. These areas of natural beauty were later among the first National Parks in the United States. The designation of vast tracts of land in the West as National Parks came about in response to the paintings and writings of many naturalists and explorers, such as John Muir, Thomas Moran and John Wesley Powell, in the late nineteenth century and early twentieth. A need was seen for areas of spectacular natural beauty to be set aside and left in their natural conditions for visitors to marvel at. And marvel they have, even back to the first sightings of one of these places, the Grand Canyon.These early visitors are the ones to whom belongs the credit for the picturesque, often exotic landform names to be found in the Parks. Even the most casual glance at these names shows that most of them fall into one of a number of categories based on their origins, i.e. names from ancient religions or mythologies. This observation led the author to the thought that names in a given category might show a tendency to occur in one area and be sparce or nonexistant in another. The Grand Canyon was chosen for site of this study, for the Park contains a great variety of place names. Originally, I to determine the dates when the names were given, and compare these to the dates of similar names given in other National Parks established at about the same time. However, the material on place names in other Parks is not nearly as extensive as that for the Grand Canyon, and that information rarely indicates when names were given, if it is even known. Therefore, I decided to limit this study to the names in the Grand Canyon, and leave out entirely the question of when features were named.</abstract><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57648</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">All Rights Reserved</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>