<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>The Significance and Implementation of Geographic Information Systems for Cities</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Otto-Finnegan, Peggy</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1988, November</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>In this day and age cities are growing, not only in size, but in complexity which has greatly increased their information needs. The complexity of administrative requirements imposed by new and expanding governmental programs and regulations has created even more data that cities will need to handle. In addition to this growth in the amount of information needed, there is also a need to obtain information in different forms to meet changing legal requirements. At the same time, traditional and routine day-to-day information that is generated and processed must continue to be stored. A city planning department, for example, collects a variety of land related information on a daily basis. Planning and building applications come in with deeds, surveys, and development plans attached. In most cities this information will remain in the case files as a matter of permanent record, creating a vast amount of stored paper. In addition to this, the public is continually requesting information which has to be looked up, either on a map or in one of several record books. They may be asking for information on floodplains or zoning, which must be given in correct precise legal form or the city employee giving the information could be held legally
accountable. Most city departments information which must be are generating useful and necessary stored somehow. All of these
increasing amounts of information are coming at a time when the economic vitality of cities is decreasing, and tax bases are dwindling. In fact, Colorado recently had a proposal where taxation could not be increased without voter approval, with elections allowed only once every two years. While this particular legislative measure did not pass, several other states already have such tax limitation laws and still others can
anticipate taxation laws similar to this. As a result, many cities may have increased needs with no increases in tax based revenue. Budget cuts are already frequent and planning departments along with other city agencies are often targets of personnel reductions. The result is fewer people doing the same work as before plus responding to new needs and requirements. With recent advances in technology, the possibility of
automating land information is a reality for more cities. Just a few years ago data bases for cities were kept on mainframes. Today with the arrival of mini and personal computers, mainframes are not always needed for the same type of storage, analysis, and output. The mini and personal computers are also less expensive than mainframes which may enable more cities to participate in automation, especially smaller ones. The question now becomes whether or not recent advances in geographic information systems (GISs) can provide solutions for
cities to save time and money within a limited resource environment, and if so, how does a community go about selecting and implementing such a system? The research setting for this study will be metropolitan Denver, Colorado. Answers to these research questions have been pursued in two phases. First, selected metropolitan Denver area cities were surveyed as to their experience with automation. These
communities constitute a variety of different sizes, some of which have automated or are considering automation and others which have not automated. Questions related to why they have automated will be addressed. Second, a case study of the City of Wheat Ridge, Colorado which recently became involved with automating their municipal data will be examined. This case study along with the findings from other case studies reported in the literature will be incorporated into guidelines covering the main aspects of setting up a municipal GIS. To date there have been no in depth studies examining the developmental process of automating information systems for cities. This study will assist cities with limited capital in arriving at a decision of whether to automate, and if so to identify issues concerning the subsequent design of their own GIS. The guidelines that will be presented in this study are based on &quot;hands-on&quot; experience and should prove useful in
avoiding the major problems of setting up a municipal GIS.</abstract><note>Research Project</note><subject></subject><subject></subject><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><subject><name type="personal"></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"></name></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:60690</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>