<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>The Relationship Between Expansive Soils and Housing Turnover</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Graczyk, Richard J.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><name type="corporate"><namePart>Geography</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">sponsor</roleTerm></role></name><name type="corporate"><namePart>University of Denver</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">degree grantor</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateIssued keyDate="yes">1980 May</dateIssued><publisher>University of Denver</publisher><dateCreated>1980</dateCreated></originInfo><language><languageTerm type="text">en</languageTerm></language><abstract>Past studies on residential mobility have examined the relationship between a number of variables and housing turnover. This list of variables includes life cycle stage, housing tenure, racial character of the neighborhood, marital status of household head, income and numerous others. In most cases, however, physical site factors such as slope stability, drainage characteristics of the residential plot, ability of the soil to sustain an attractive landscape, or shrink-swell characteristics of the soil are seldom mentioned. This paper will explore the latter problem in greater detail. Each year, natural disasters such as hurricanes, tornadoes, and earthquakes attract widespread television and newspaper coverage. This increases public awareness of these hazards. To be sure, the loss potential of these natural phenomena is enormous as well as highly visible. The damage caused by expansive souls, however, is also quite large but is incurred over a longer period of time rather than in a single large scale dramatic event.</abstract><note>Move to Papers</note><note displayLabel="degree name">master</note><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><name type="personal"></name></subject><subject><name type="corporate"></name></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57358</url></location><accessCondition type="userandreproduction">All Rights Reserved</accessCondition><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright is held by the author.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>