<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>COASTAL GEOMORPHOLOGICAL DATA MANAGEMENT, ANALYSIS, AND Visualization: An Assateague Island National Seashore Case Study</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Ransmeier, Melanie V.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">2005 June</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>The northern end of Assateague Island National Seashore (ASIS) has migrated more than 400 meters toward mainland Maryland since Ocean City Inlet was stabilized by jetties following a major hurricane in 1933. This migration dramatically illustrates the dynamic nature of coastal systems. Geomorphological monitoring is crucial to understanding both the natural fluctuations of barrier islands and anthropogenic influences on coastal change. In order for monitoring data to be effective they must be properly collected, managed, utilized in appropriate analyses, and presented to resource stewards and the public in a meaningful way. This project addresses these needs by instituting a functional data management protocol, illustrating appropriate analytical techniques, and providing a geo-temporal data visualization model for ASIS&apos;s coastal geomorphologic data. The data management protocol documents methods and procedures for collecting, processing, distributing, and storing geomorphologic data. Analytical techniques explored and described include: historic shoreline change analysis, morphologic change surface creation, and comparison of traditional and topographic lidar derived cross-island profiles. The data visualization website provides a three dimensional time sequence animation of changing island morphology. Data management adds increased value to geomorphologic data for monitoring, analysis, and reporting. Illustrating analytical techniques enables natural resource staff and managers to explore the meaning that coastal geomorphologic data can impart by highlighting the potential for displaying and quantifying coastal change. Visualizing coastal change is important for understanding the dynamic nature of coastal environments. Each of these elements, as addressed in this project, enhances the coastal monitoring program in place at ASIS.</abstract><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:58126</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>