<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>A Geographic Information System for the Mount Evans Region</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Dover, Melissa Ann</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1995 August</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>Mount Evans, at an elevation of 4,348 meters (14,264 feet) and located in the Front Range of Colorado, strikes an impressive view looking west from Denver. Originally a portion of an ancestral range of the late Precambrian time, Mount Evans is now only an erosion remnant of a huge granitic batholith (Griffiths and Rubright 1983). Water, ice, wind and gravity have carved this majestic range, and continue to be the dominating natural forces shaping these mountains. The Front Range acts as a watershed for streams and groundwater, a source of valuable minerals, an area for commercial timber activities, a pasture for livestock and perhaps most intensely, as a recreational escape for close-by city dwellers and tourists. According to a Denver Post article dated September 13, 1994, more than 71,000 vehicles drove to the summit of Mount Evans in a three month period during the summer.Mount Evans&apos; close proximity to Denver has enabled the University of Denver to develop a research area for its faculty and students which supports many diverse research topics. The wide range of natural resource topics being researched in the area make the Mount Evans region a prime candidate for a Geographic Information System (GIS). GIS is defined as an information technology which can input, store, manipulate, analyze and display spatial and non-spatial data. A GIS can be the integrating tool that allows disparate information formats such as vector, raster, image or Database Management Systems (DBMS) to be brought together under a common framework for access and analysis (ESRI 1992). &quot;A GIS organizes geographic data using a georelational and topological model which facilitates efficient handling of the two generic classes of spatial data: locational data, graphically describing the location and topology of point, line, and area features; and attribute data, the information describing the characteristics of these features.&quot; (ESRI 1992, p.12) In order to better serve the University of Denver&apos;s Geography department&apos;s research projects, a GIS was designed and implementation begun using Environmental Systems Research Institute&apos;s (ESRI) PC ARC/INFO GIS software, to facilitate efficient and high quality data manipulation and mapping of the Mount Evans region.</abstract><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57895</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>