<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>To PUD or Not to PUD: An Inventory of the Extent and Utilization of the PUD Concept in Metropolitan Denver.</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Luhrs, Kurt A.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1980 May</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>Positive results were observed with respect to the hypothesis that perimeter cities and their respective counties will adopt PUD ordinances before inner cities. Analysis of the data showed that perimeter cities and counties did adopt their PUD ordinances before inner cities. This was due in part to the significantly higher rate of growth of perimeter cities. Because PUD was oriented toward large scale development perimeter cities probably adopted this ordinance to better control the increased population growth by offering large scale planned developments.Spatial Group Comparisons.There were many similarities between inner and perimeter cities and unincorporated urban areas when the key ordinance provisions,implementation procedures and development trends were compared. This means that PUD is being used in the same manner throughout the region. Perimeter cities did have a higher percentage of PUD projects for a three year average than did counties. Inner cities seemed to have a limited amount of growth but among these cities there was a growing number of PUD&apos;s. Inner cities appear to be in the process of increasing their use of PUD to guide the development of the limited amount of vacant land available. Use of the PUD Concept Perimeter cities did make the most consistent use of the PUD concept.Thornton and Aurora were the two cities that appeared to make the most consistent use of the concept. Aurora seemed to be using the concept less, in 1978 than during the post adoption period. Thornton is increasing their use of PUD almost to the exclusion of standard zoning and sub¬division regulations. This difference in use of the concept over time is probably due in part to the detailed ordinance used by Aurora and the very general ordinance that Thornton uses.</abstract><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57511</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>