<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Development of a Geographic Information System Database for Woodland Park, Colorado a Pilot Project</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Rodeck, Paul P.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1992 August</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>The Teller county Planning Offices are currently engaged in the preliminary stages of creating a Geographic Information System (GIS). It is the purpose of this project to facilitate the planning offices in their development of the GIS. The clients of the project are Mr. Larry Larsen, the city Planner of Woodland Park, and Mr. Kip Petersen, the County Planner. The pilot project described in this document provides the procedures of the GIS necessary to make the GIS operational. (Please also note this document assumes user has a working knowledge of AutoCAD and understands basic GIS concepts.) The system is designed to facilitate: 1} organization and maintenance of planning data; 2} the processing of data to provide answers to specific questions; and 3} additional data storage and expansion of the information system. The agreed upon final product of this project, in addition to the development of the GIS system, was a series of land use GIS database files for Woodland Park, Colorado to assist local planners in their GIS development. pilot development of GIS technology is important to the Woodland Park planners because it will provide Woodland Park with a geographic information system which incorporates both graphic and attribute elements in the database. The County Planning Offices are currently in the early stages of initiating a GIS. The first objective was to develop the general design of the GIS and to make it operational. The second was to develop several data files, including a base map which can be used with subsequent map overlays. The City and County planners will be able to maintain, utilize, and update the system by entering new data into the database through a user-interface. This system will allow the planning offices to perform existing tasks in new and more efficient ways when it comes to storing, encoding, and analyzing information that before may have taken several days to complete. Constant updates and production of overlays and hard copy maps may be produced as needed within the planning office itself. Planning offices will be able to use the GIS to assist in the development of a growth management plan, daily activities, and long term planning ideas. Manipulating or combining the data in any way the user desires .may provide new information and assist in meeting future needs. Different alternatives of the planning process can be generated in terms of either graphic display (i.e. maps, diagrams, designs) or data (Hanson, 1987). Finally, the initial systems will allow planners to use Geo/Sql as the foundation on which to build new functions into their GIS and update and expand the database as needed.</abstract><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:57892</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>