<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Weather Modification Research Project</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Peterman, William A.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><place><placeTerm>University of Denver Department of Geography</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1970</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>From 20 July to 8 August 1970 an experiment in decision making was conducted by the University of Denver with the assistance of scientists from DAWRM and MRI. The results from this experiment are encouraging in that they indicate that (1) decision making can be used to increase the efficiency of precipitation management experiments and (2) the meteorological information network, developed in part by the University of Denver, is a valuable tool for use by decision maker. Largely, as a result of this experiment the decision was made by the DAWRM to initiate the meteorological information network on an operational basis for the 1970-71 wintertime seeding. This was accomplished during November 1971. Thus, beginning at that time, all Project Skywater field programs had available all of the tools and data for decision making available to the scientists at the Flagstaff project. It is felt that the implementation of this network represents a significant step toward the development of a well coordinated precipitation management program. The implementation of the network is only the first step needed to make available decision-making techniques to field users. Many improvements are yet needed. Among these are more efficient processes for collecting, storing, and disseminating data, expanded data bases, and a greater diversity of programs and models. The first step has been taken. Let us hope that the remaining steps will soon follow and that decision making will become truly an integral part of precipitation management research.</abstract><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55654</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>