<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>Developing an Interface Between ArcView GIS and the Industrial Source Complex Model A Case Study in Denver, Colorado</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Holtkamp, Christopher Ray</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1999 June</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>The interactive tool developed for this project is designed to allow users to access the air pollution modeling capabilities of the Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s Industrial Source Complex (lSC) model then use the capabilities of Arc View GIS, developed by Environmental Systems Research Institute (ESRI), to display and analyze the results. The goal is to allow non-technical users a relatively simple means of modeling the dispersion of air pollution quickly and easily. This report is intended to discuss the process that went into creating the interactive tool and how the final product evolved from the ideas that began this project; it is not intended as a user&apos;s guide for the interactive tool. This report will begin with the background of the project, describing the original idea. It will then discuss problems and decisions that were made during the development process that influenced the final product. It will then discuss the actual development of the interactive tool and the different applications used. This report will end with a discussion of how this tool can be applied and areas of future work that can build on this tool to expand the capabilities.</abstract><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:58117</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>