<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"><titleInfo><title>An Assessment of the Usefulness of Small-Scale Photographic Imagery for Acquiring Land Use Information Necessary to the Urban Planning Function</title></titleInfo><name type="personal"><namePart>Howard, William A.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><name type="personal"><namePart>Kracht, James B.</namePart><role><roleTerm authority="marcrelator" type="text">creator</roleTerm></role></name><typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource><originInfo><place><placeTerm>University of Denver Department of Geography</placeTerm></place><dateCreated keyDate="yes">1971</dateCreated></originInfo><abstract>This study concerns the feasibility of remote sensing techniques contributing to the data needs of urban planning. The primary question investigated is whether planning information inputs can be modified to be compatible with current remote sensor output formats and whether these output formats are alterable enough to become compatible with planning input needs. Small scale imagery at 1:50,000 and 1:100,000 in conventional color and color infrared is used to determine the extent to which land use types can be discriminated. The larger scale is most useful and generalized information at a one-digit level can be identified with more detailed information at a two-digit level also possible. The smaller of the scales is only useful for one-digit discrimination and only a very few land use types at a two-digit level of detail. The present formats of remote sensing are suited to the planner’s needs and offer promise as a data source if available on a routine basis and at frequent intervals. However, small-scale imagery must possess high resolution and be of very good quality.</abstract><subject><topic>Geology</topic></subject><subject><topic>Geography</topic></subject><location><url usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10176/codu:55655</url></location><accessCondition type="useandreproduction">Copyright restrictions may apply. User is responsible for all copyright compliance.</accessCondition><recordInfo><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="text">English</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging></recordInfo></mods>